<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jenkins Operator – How it works</title>
    <link>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/</link>
    <description>Recent Hugo news from gohugo.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/img/hugo.png</url>
      <title>GoHugo.io</title>
      <link>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/</link>
    </image>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Architecture and design</title>
      <link>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/architecture-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/architecture-and-design/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Jenkins Operator&lt;/strong&gt; design incorporates the following concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watches any changes of manifests and maintain the desired state according to deployed custom resource manifest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;implements the main reconciliation loop which consists of two smaller reconciliation loops - base and user&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/kubernetes-operator/img/reconcile.png&#34; alt=&#34;reconcile&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Base&lt;/strong&gt; reconciliation loop takes care of reconciling base Jenkins configuration, which consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Manifests - monitors any changes in manifests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Jenkins Pod - creates and verifies the status of Jenkins master Pod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Jenkins Configuration - configures Jenkins instance including hardening, initial configuration for plugins, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Jenkins API token - generates Jenkins API token and initialized Jenkins client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User&lt;/strong&gt; reconciliation loop takes care of reconciling user provided configuration, which consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Restore Job - creates Restore job and ensures that restore has been successfully performed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Seed Jobs - creates Seed Jobs and ensures that all of them have been successfully executed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure User Configuration - executed user provided configuration, like groovy scripts, configuration as code or plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure Backup Job -  creates a Backup job and ensures that backup has been successfully performed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/kubernetes-operator/img/phases.png&#34; alt=&#34;reconcile&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;operator-state&#34;&gt;Operator State&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operator state is kept in the custom resource status section, which is used for storing any configuration events or job statuses managed by the operator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to maintain or recover the desired state even after the operator or Jenkins restarts.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Jenkins Docker Images</title>
      <link>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/jenkins-docker-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jenkinsci.github.io/kubernetes-operator/docs/how-it-works/jenkins-docker-images/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jenkins Operator&lt;/strong&gt; is fully compatible with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;jenkins:lts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Docker image and does not introduce any hidden changes to the upstream Jenkins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If needed, the Docker image can be easily changed in custom resource manifest as long as it supports standard Jenkins file system structure.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>